DHARMENDRA PATEL

Senior Software Engineer

H.NO.31, 1st main 4th cross BEML Layout, Bangalore, Karnataka 560037 | +91-7087785263 | dharmendra80808@gmail.com

Professional Summary

In total 10+ years (including 6 years in ios native, 5 years in React Native & React JS) of Web and Mobile Apps development experience.

Skilled with Javascript, HTML, DOM, REDUX, REST to develop REACT JS application, Swift, Objective-C, XCode to develop iOS native apps, React Native to develop iOS and android apps as well.

3 React app, 2 React JS website, 18 iOS published on Apple App Store.

Experienced with Java script, Visual studio, iOS SDK, Cocoa Touch, Android SDK, integrating third-party libraries and APIs. Strong database and front-end skills.

Skilled at software design using UML and applying design patterns.

Quality focus – unit, functional and regression testing.

Strong technical writing skills.

Constantly learning, evaluating, and applying new technologies and best practices, such as Agile.

Skills

- Operating Systems: Windows, mac OS X, Android OS 4.0 and above.
- Technologies/Language: React js, React-Native Swift, Objective C, Cocoa Touch, iOS SDK, Android OS,
- Database: Core Data, SQLite3, MySQL.
- Tools/Editors: XCode v6-9, Android Studio v2-3, Visual Studio Code, PSPad

Work History

Senior Software Engineer

Decision Minds India Pvt. Ltd.

Senior Software Engineer

Brihaspati infotech Pvt Ltd.

Software Engineer

Mobilyte India Pvt. Ltd

Software Engineer

Sebiz infotechPvt Ltd.

Feb 2019 - Present Bengaluru, Karnataka

Apr 2018 - Feb 2019 Mohali, Punjab

March 2016 - March 2018 Mohali, Punjab

June 2011 - March 2016 Mohali, PUNJAB

Education

MCA in Technology: UPTU

RBS Collage of Agra UP

2011

Agra, U.P

Projects

1: Synergy:

Webapp: http://synergy.vmware.com

• Environment: Ide: Visual Studio

• Roles : Senior Developer front end

Functionalities:

Vmware has multiple clients and account so for tracking all activities and client relationship health this app created which shows all accounts on Home Page. Also we can generate report according to accounts. Client can forcast plans for feature and we can track.

App provides all closed and open accout in one place.

So App trackes all client's account in one place.

2: FirstTech: iOS: https://apps.apple.com/ph/app/first-tech-federal-cu/id1072402877

Environment: Ide: VSCode, Compatibility: ios 9—13.0, Dev.Env: Mac OS X Mojave

Roles: Senior Developer

Functionality: First Tech app has the digital banking tools you need to manage your money.

Other features are as Acccount Management, Money movement, Bill Payment, Transfer money & Send Money with Zelle etc.

3: Vintage Camera Glitch FX:

- iOS: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vintage-camera-glitch-retro-fx/id1447477363?ls=1&mt=8
- Environment: Ide: Xcode, Compatibility: ios 9.0+, Dev.Env: Mac OS
- Roles : Senior Developer
- Functionalities: Senior This App is prepare for creating vintage videios in old Formate.

4: Hangarbot: (Product)

• iOS: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hangarbot/id1230197363?mt=8

Compatibility: ios 9.0 and above

Roles : Senior Developer

• Functionalities: This app is prepare for control hardware Devices like, Camera, Door

control, Wifi outlets etc. App.

5: Blink4: (Quiz App using React Native)

React-Native - iOS: https://itunes.apple.com/gb/app/blink4/id909254283?mt=8

Roles: Senior Developer

• Functionalities: This is Quiz Game App. App Open Login, Sign Up and after that Home

View shows with 4 cards having optional quistios - and play game given answers. If we

give correct 50 answers out of 60 then we got credits according answer points.

6: Strategiegames: (Gameing app for Chess, Checker and Dies)

iOS: https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/strategiegames/id1273802017?ls=1&mt=8

Roles: Senior Developer

Functionalities: This is online gaming app having 3 games (Chess, Checker and Dies). We can

Play online by connecting our friends.

Personal Information

• Date of Birth: 10-Jul-1986.

• Gender: Male

• Marital Status: Married

• Father's Name: Mr. Mata Badal Patel

Hobbies: Playing Cricket and Curious to

learn new things

DECLARATION: - I hereby declare that the information given above is correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date:

Place: Bangalore

(Dharmendra Patel)